A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Paris Field Office files FA724
Rockefeller Archive Center
- General Correspondence, III
  - General - "H" (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - General - "I" (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - General - "J" (Box 8, Folder 202)
  - General - "K" (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - General - "L" (Box 8, Folder 204)
  - General - "M" (Box 8, Folder 205)
  - General - "N" (Box 8, Folder 206)
  - General - "O" (Box 8, Folder 207)
  - General - "P" (Box 8, Folder 208)
  - General - "R" (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - General - "S" (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - General - "T" (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - General - "U" (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - General - "V" (Box 9, Folder 213)
  - General - "W" (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - General - "Y" (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - General - "Z" (Box 9, Folder 216)
- Chronological Correspondence, IV
  Series IV, Chronological Correspondence ("chrons"), contains copies of all correspondence emanating out of the Paris field office. It has been kept in the order in which it was found.
  Series IV is arranged in reverse chronological order. These files were kept in their original order.
  - 1974 October 1 - December 30 (Box 9, Folder 217)
  - 1974 July 1 - September 30 (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - 1974 May 2 - June 28 (Box 9, Folder 219)
  - 1974 March 1 - April 30 (Box 10, Folder 220)
  - 1974 January 2 - February 28 (Box 10, Folder 221)
  - 1973 November 2 - December 28 (Box 10, Folder 222)
  - 1973 August 1 - October 31 (Box 10, Folder 223)
  - 1973 May 2 - July 31 (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - 1973 March 1 - April 30 (Box 11, Folder 225)
  - 1973 January 2 - February 28 (Box 11, Folder 226)
  - 1972 November 1 - December 30 (Box 11, Folder 227)
  - 1972 September 1 - October 31 (Box 11, Folder 228)
  - 1972 July 1 - August 31 (Box 11, Folder 229)
  - 1972 May 3 - June 28 (Box 11, Folder 230)
  - 1972 March 23 - April 26 (Box 11, Folder 231)
- Appendix A: Ford Foundation Reports Removed
  The following unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff, consultants and grantees were removed from the Paris Field Office files and transferred to the Archives' collection of unpublished reports. They are listed alphabetically by author. The number to the left of the reports is the assigned accession number.
  - Ball, Nicole and Dahlberg, Kenneth A. Political Considerations within International Organizations, 1973 February (Report 11786)
  - Beckett, J. C. Northern Ireland (Report 11796)
  - Bergsten, C. Fred. The United States and Germany: The Imperative of Economic Bigemony (Report 11782)
  - Chalfont, Baron Arthur. The Significant Aspects of Military Security in the Conflict Area (Report 11796)
  - Crozier, Brian. Communist-led Insurrections in the 1970s, 1971 January (Report 11796)
  - Derriennic, Jean-Pierre. Report on French Studies in International Politics, 1974 October (Report 2035)
  - FitzGerald, Garret. Ireland in the Context of the European Community (Report 11796)
  - Ford Foundation. European and International Affairs: Conference on Foundation Programs in Europe, February 24-25, 1971, 1971 March (Report 4993)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation and Western Europe, 1950-1970, 1971-1975 (Report 19492)
  - Ford Foundation. U.S.-European Relations in a Changing World, 1973 February (Report 11941)
  - Ford Foundation. Report of the Internal Foundation Conference on Ford Foundation Programs in Europe, Feb. 24-25, 1971, 1971 July (Report 2800)
  - Ford Foundation. Report on an Exploration of Grant-Making Possibilities in Vietnam, 1974 March (Report 6437)
  - Ford Foundation. The Shrinking Gap, 1970 (Report 10986)
  - Ford Foundation. Spain: Trip Report, October 23 - November 19, 1968, 1968 November (Report 4574)
  - Frodin, Reuben. Assistance to Vietnam in the Field of Education, 1974 January (Report 2415)
  - Gasteyger, Curt W. Reports on Current Research Relating to Problems of European Security, Arms Control and East-West Relations (4 Reports), 1972 January - August (Report 11944)
  - Goodwillie, Susan. Report on Visits to European Development, Research and Training Organizations, 26 March - 9 April 1974 (Report 11945)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd & Silj, Alessandro. Ireland, 1972 June (Report 9044)
  - Griffith, William E. Soviet-American Detente and American Relations with the Federal Republic: Prepared for the Eighth American-German Conference, Bonn, November 17-19, 1974, 1974 October (Report 11958)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Informal Notes on Bellagio Population Conference Discussion, 1971 June (Report 9549)
  - Haupt, Georges. Russian and East European Studies in France, 1972 (Report 11953)
  - Higgins, Rosalyn. Human Rights and the Ford Foundation, 1973 March (Report 11952)
  - Shamsul Huq, Muhammad. Whither Growth? - A Case Study of Bangladesh, India and Pakistan, 1970 (Report 11955)
  - Jacqz, Jane W. U.S. and European Investment in Africa: Report of a Conference on United States and European Investment in Africa held at the Abbey Royaumont Paris, France, 1969 (Report 11975)
  - Jacqz, Jane W. France and the United States in 1970: Report of a Conference of French and American Journalists, Bellagio (Como), Italy, May 22-24, 1970 (Report 11966)
  - Johnston, Larry A. Survey of International Studies in the United Kingdom, 1974 June (Report 11964)
  - Kimball, Merritt E. CASTAFRICA Conference, Dakar, 21-30 January, 1974, 1974 February 5 (Report 11989)
  - Kohl, W. L. EIA Program for International Affairs Institutes and Related Activities, 1970 July (Report 5062)
  - Kohl, W. L. EIA Program for West European Studies in American Universities, 1970 July (Report 2429)
  - Latapi, Pablo. Review Report on the CRIDE (Unaza, Zaire), 1973 July (Report 4242)
  - Lederer, Ivo J. Some Aspects of "National Insecurity" in the Russian Experience, 1970 (Report 11949)
  - Lyons, F. S. L. The Alternatives Open to Governments (Report 11796)
  - Mackintosh, John P. An Evaluation of the Existing State of International Studies in the United Kingdom, 1974 July (Report 11965)
  - Merriam, John Edwin. Program Recommendations Regarding Communal Conflict on the Island of Cyprus: a Report to the Ford Foundation, 1970 (Report 11957)
  - Miettinen, Jorma K. European Security Balanced by Tactical Nuclear Weapons?, 1972 (Report 11963)
  - Morin, Francoise. On Haitians in New York: Report on Research in New York, 1974 (Report 11980)
  - Pierre, Andrew J. After Watergate and the Year of Europe: The Next Phase in Trans-Atlantic Relations, 1974 October (Report 11986)
  - Piore, Michael. Letter from an American Economist in Paris, 1975 May (Report 11978)
  - Silj, Alessandro. Foundation Programs in Western Europe: A Framework, 1970 July (Report 5181)
  - Silj, Alessandro. Institutional Change (and Public Policy) -- a Discussion of Possible EIA and Foundation Strategies, 1971 September (Report 8640)
  - Weiskel, Timothy. Report on French African Studies, 1972 November (Report 11962)